--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 铭瑄
招募Q号:76846146
w
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 铭瑄
招募Q号:76846146
ww
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 铭瑄
招募Q号:76846146
www
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 铭瑄
招募Q号:76846146
www.
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 铭瑄
招募Q号:76846146
www.H
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 铭瑄
招募Q号:76846146
www.HD
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 铭瑄
招募Q号:76846146
www.HDc
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 铭瑄
招募Q号:76846146
www.HDcm
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 铭瑄
招募Q号:76846146
www.HDcmc
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 铭瑄
招募Q号:76846146
www.HDcmct
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 铭瑄
招募Q号:76846146
www.HDcmct.
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 铭瑄
招募Q号:76846146
www.HDcmct.c
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 铭瑄
招募Q号:76846146
www.HDcmct.co
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 铭瑄
招募Q号:76846146
www.HDcmct.com
【非 常 嫌 疑 犯】
圣佩德罗  加利福尼亚  昨晚
情况怎么样，基顿？
How you doing, Keaton?
我的双腿失去了知觉…
I can't feel my legs...
凯撒
Keyser
准备好了吗？
Ready?
现在是什么时候了？
What time is it?
十二点半
12:30
一切得从六星期前的纽约说起
It all started back in New York six weeks ago.
一辆满载枪械部件的卡车，在皇后区外被劫持了
A truck loaded with stripped gun parts got jacked outside of Queens.
那司机没有看到劫持者的相貌
The driver didn't see anyone, but someone fucked up.
只听到对方说的一句话，有时候这些线索就够了
He heard a voice. Sometimes that's all you need.
纽约市   六星期前
- 麦克麦纳斯先生？ - 天！就他妈不能让我睡个安稳觉？
- Mr.McManus? - Christ! Don't you fucking guys ever sleep?
- 我们被授权将你拘留 - 去死吧，猪
- We have a warrant for your arrest. - Fuck you, pig.
托德·霍克尼
Todd Hockney?
- 是谁找我？ - 我们是纽约市警局的
- Who wants to know? - New York Police Department.
- 该死的 - 不许动！
- Shit. - Freeze!
别动！
Hold it!
你们还真是如临大敌
Sure you brought enough guys?
这很简单:
It's quite simple:
餐厅的食物更换口味， 而毫不丧失其整体的艺术感
A restaurant that changes with the taste without losing the overall aesthetic.
换而言之…
In other words...
…气氛并不是由装饰来营造的
...the atmosphere will not be painted on the walls.
- 让我举例来说-- - 这得我自己来判断
- Let me give you an example-- - This I had to see for myself.
大卫
David
- 我在谈公事 - 还有别的公事等你去谈
- I'm in a meeting. - Time for another one.
我来介绍一下，这位是大卫·奎恩
Everyone, this is David Kujan.
美国海关特别探员奎恩
Special Agent Kujan. US Customs.
这几位是纽约市警局的
These gentlemen are from the New York Police Department.
你气色不错，比我想象的还要好
You look good. Better than I would have thought.
不过是关于运枪车被劫的小麻烦
A small matter of a stolen truck loaded with guns.
基顿先生？
Mr.Keaton?
请原谅，我要失陪一下
Will you excuse us for a moment?
我们得带你回局里去问话，事情不是三两句就说的清的
We have some questions to ask you downtown. You'll be a while.
不，不，请坐下
No. Please, sit down.
不过是些小事
This is a small problem.
请慢用，我们迟些再谈
Enjoy the meal. I'll talk to you later.
我根本没理由会出现在那里
It didn't make sense that I'd be there.
这些家伙本是恶贯满盈的江洋大盗
These guys were hard-core hijackers...
…而我却也被列在其中
...but there I was.
不过我当时并不害怕
At that point, I wasn't scared.
我清楚自己是清白的，他们也不能拿我怎么样
I knew I hadn't done anything they could do me for.
此外，这过程很有趣
Besides, it was fun.
我得把自己也当成是声名狼藉的罪犯
I got to make like I was notorious.
你们都知道程序
You all know the drill.
被叫到号的人就上前一步，念出纸上的话
When your number is called, step forward and repeat the phrase you've been given.
一号，上前
Number 1, step forward.
“把钥匙给我，混蛋”
"Hand me the keys you fucking cocksucker."
二号，上前
Number 2, step forward.
“把他妈钥匙给我，你这该死的混蛋！”
Gimme the fuckin' keys, you fuckin' cocksucker motherfucker!
停，退后，三号上前
Knock it off. Get back. Number 3, step forward.
- “把钥匙给我，混蛋” - 请讲英语
- "Hand me the keys, you cocksucker." - In English, please.
- 你说什么？ - 请讲英语
- Excuse me? - In English.
“把钥匙给我，混蛋” ，这哪儿不对了？
Hand me the fuckin' keys, you cocksucker. What the fuck?
四号上前
Number 4, step forward.
这根本是胡来，全都是栽赃嫁祸
It was bullshit. The whole rap was a setup.
“把钥匙给我，混蛋”
"Hand me the keys you fucking cocksucker."
全是警察的错
It was the cops' fault.
像这样的人根本不该关在一起
You don't put guys like that into a room together.
谁知道会发生些什么？
Who knows what can happen?
“把钥匙给我，混蛋”
"Hand me the keys you fucking cocksucker."
这事情一定让你们很头痛
This has really got to be embarrassing for you guys.
他们审了我们整晚上
They drilled us all night.
运枪车被劫，有人暴跳如雷，而警察们却束手无策
Someone was mad about that truck hijacking and the cops had nothing.
所以希望有人会撞到他们枪口上来
They were hoping somebody would slip up and give them something.
他们清楚我们不能反抗，他们知道该怎么向我们施加压力
They knew we wouldn't fight, they knew how to lean on us.
他们一直就是如此，我们的权利早被践踏的没影了
They've been doing it forever. Our rights went out the window.
那简直就是可耻的亵渎人权
It was a violation. Disgraceful.
他们最先审问的是麦克麦纳斯，他是个打家劫舍的老手
They went after McManus first. Topnotch entry man.
什么卡车？
What truck?
- 运枪的卡车，杂种  - “杂种”？
- The truck with the guns, fucko. - "Fucko"?
他是个好人，只是有时会有点疯狂
He was a good guy. Crazy, though.
想知道你的好兄弟范斯特是怎么说的？
Wanna know what your pal Fenster told us?
- 说谁？ - 麦克麦纳斯
- Say who? - McManus.
他说的完全是另外一个情况
He told us another story.
是说那个得了痢疾的妓女吗？
Is that the one about the hooker with the dysentery?
范斯特总是和麦克麦纳斯一起干，是个油腔滑调的家伙
Fenster always worked with McManus. He was a real tight-ass.
但是说到正事上来，他确实算是个聪明人
But when it came to the job, he was right on. A smart man.
- 你说什么？ - 我说他会教训你的
- What are you saying? - I said he'll flip you.
- 他会什么？ - 教训你，狠狠的教训你
- He'll what? - Flip you. Flip you for real.
- 我怕极了，继续 - 好吧
- I'm shaking. Come on. - Okay.
- 回答我的问题 - 后面那位也听的清吗？
- Answer my questions. - Can you hear me in the back?
喂？
Hello?
我要见律师
I want my lawyer.
我要让你们这些该死的警察丢掉饭碗
I'm gonna have your fuckin' badge, cocksucker.
托德·霍克尼:爆破专家
Todd Hockney: good with explosives.
毫无疑问，这家伙不会出卖任何人
Without a doubt, the one guy who didn't give a fuck about anybody.
你们根本没有他妈的证据
You guys don't have a fuckin' leg to stand on.
你以为是吗？
You think so, tough guy?
我能以在皇后区抢劫货车的罪名起诉你
I can put you in Queens during the hijacking.
是吗？
Really?
我就住在皇后区
I live in Queens.
所以你就这么把事情凑在一起告我，爱因思坦？
Did you put that together yourself, Einstein?
你的那群猴子手下就是这么办事的？
You got a team of monkeys working full time on this?
知道你若是再投胎，会怎样？
You know what happens if you do another turn in the joint?
我会狂干你老爸
I fuck your father in the shower, and have a snack.
- 你想告我吗？白痴 - 我会随时控告你
- Are you gonna charge me, dickhead? - I'll charge you when I'm ready.
- 凭什么来告我？ - 你自己心里很清楚
- With what? - You know damn well, dead man.
基顿？
But Keaton?
基顿是他们重点审问的目标
Keaton was the real prize for them for obvious reasons.
犯错的是你们，而不是我
It was your mistake, not mine.
你们到底问完了没有？
Did you ever stop to ask me?
我坐不改名，行不改姓
I've been walking around with the same face, the same name.
是个正经商人
I'm a businessman.
做什么生意？餐厅生意？
What's that? The restaurant business?
现在你要做的就是给我老实招供
No. From now on you're in the "getting fucked by us" business.
我会把你绳之以法的，混蛋
I'm gonna make you famous, cocksucker.
我已经说了…
Like I said...
…犯错的是你们
...it was your mistake
…而不是我
...not mine.
你们要是胡乱控诉我
You charge me with this shit...
…我一定会反诉你们
...and I'll beat it.
明白吗？
Okay?
继续说卡车的事吧，混蛋
Let's get back to the truck, asshole.
真该有人管管这破事
Really, somebody's got to do something about this shit.
他们动不动就找我麻烦，我真是受够了
They put me in holding every five minutes. So I did a little time.
难道说每丢辆卡车，就都得把我关进来？
Does that mean I get railed every time a truck finds it's way gone?
让他们去死吧
Fuck 'em.
范斯特，放松点好吗？
Fenster, will you relax?
- 他们根本没有任何证据 - 你说的对，无凭无据
- These guys don't have any probable cause. - You fuckin' right. No PC.
真他妈说的太对了，只要曾犯过小错，他们就会揪住你不放
You're goddamn right. You do some time, never let you go.
他们当我是罪犯般看待
They treat me like a criminal.
- 那么我迟早也会变成个罪犯 - 你本来就是罪犯
- I'll end up a criminal. - You are a criminal.
干嘛说的那么直接？
Why'd you got to go and do that?
- 我只是在做假设 - 做你的假设去吧
- I'm trying to make a point. - Why don't you make your point?
你让我烦透了
You're making me tired all over.
去死吧
Fuck it then.
- 我听说你已经死了 - 是吗？
- I heard you were dead. - Yeah?
- 你没有听错 - 我听说的是你已经收手不干了
- You heard right. - Word I got is you hung up your spurs.
- 这是怎么回事？ - 究竟怎么说的？
- What's that all about? - What's this?
谣言说基顿已经改过自新，还和伊迪·菲娜琳打的火热
Rumor has it Keaton's gone straight. I hear he's tapping Edie Finneran.
那是谁？
Who's that?
她是重量级的刑事辩护律师
She's a heavyweight criminal lawyer from uptown.
听说她成了基顿的饭票
I hear she's Keaton's meal ticket.
是吗，基顿？
How 'bout it, Keaton?
你有个当律师的妻子？
You a lawyer's wife?
你是怎么勾上她的？
What kind of retainer you giving her?
帮帮忙，让他保持安静
Do your friend a favor...tell him to keep quiet.
迪恩·基顿…
Dean Keaton...
改过自新？
Gone clean?
我觉得不可能
Say it ain't so.
- 还是说卡车就是你抢的？ - 麦克，算了吧
- Or was it you that hit that truck? - Mac, forget him.
你和律师谈过没有？
Did you get to talk to your lawyer?
整件事情不过是借口
This whole thing was a shakedown.
- 为什么这么说？ - 你被指认过几次？
- What makes you say that? - How many times you been in a lineup?
通常总是你和四个不相干的人
It's always you and four dummies.
警方总找些流浪汉来，每次给他们十块
The PD are paying homeless guys $10 a head half the time.
他们不会同时把五个罪犯放在一起
There's no way they'd line five felons in the same row.
- 那声音指认呢？ - 那无非是形式
- What's a voice lineup?  - Public defender could get you out of that.
- 为什么要找上我？ - 是联邦调查局的家伙
- Why the hell was I strip searched? - It was the feds.
有辆运枪车被截下了
A truckload of guns gets snagged.
海关的人到纽约警局要答案，于是他们来找我们的麻烦
Customs comes down on NYPD for answers. They come up with us.
- 他们把我们当成救命稻草 - 我们就这么被他们玩
- They're clutching at straws. - I had a guy's finger up my ass.
现在是星期五了吗？
Is it Friday already?
是的，花花公子
Yeah, lover boy.
想被人修理吗？来吧，我会好好疼你的
You want a piece? Jump in. I'll love you.
那么到底是他妈的哪个人渣抢的货车？
So who in the goddamn piss hell stole our fucking truck?
- 你说什么？ - 是谁偷了那货车？
- What did you say? - Who stole the fucking truck?
- 我不想知道 - 没人问你，正经人
- I don't want to know. - Who asked you, workingman?
做这事的人去死吧，我现在想知道那跛子是什么人？
Fuck who did it. What I want to know is, who's the gimp?
- 没他的事  - 全是你在说，我怎么知道？
- He's okay. - Says you. How do I know that?
怎么样，拐脚佬？说说你的故事吧
What about it, pretzel man? What's your story?
他叫“口水先生”
His name is Verbal.
维伯·肯特
Verbal Kint.
- “口水先生”？ - 对
- Verbal? - Yeah.
真名是罗杰，人人说我话太多
Roger, really. People say I talk too much.
我正想叫你闭嘴
I was going to tell you to shut up.
- 我们以前见过一二次 - 是在州局，我因为诈骗罪被逮进了局子
- We met before, once or twice. - In County. I was in for fraud.
我们曾一同被指认，后来如何了？
You were in a lineup then, too. What happened?
被判了90天，缓刑释放
I walked. 90 days, suspended.
- 你也不是个好人 - 好了，大家听我说…
- So you did it. - All right, now look...
…我们都因这事被搅进来
...we've all been put out by this whole thing, right?
我想我们该设法挽回点面子
I figure we owe it to ourselves to salvage a little dignity.
我和范斯特听说有桩生意
Now, me and Fenster heard about a little job.
安静会儿好吗？
Why don't you just calm down?
听他说说又怎么了？
What do you care what he has to say?
我不过随便说说
I'm just talking here.
看来哈肯尼先生，似乎想听我要说什么…
It seems to me like Mr.Hockney wants to hear it...
…而我知道范斯特亦有兴趣
...and I know Fenster's down.
你呢？伙计
What about you, guy?
当然有兴趣
I'm interested.
看到没？
There. See?
我只想行使我的自由集会权
I'd like to exercise my right to free assembly.
闭会儿嘴不行吗？
Why don't you just shut up?
你是不明白
You're missing the point.
不
No.
不明白的人是你
You're missing the point.
我不想听你说任何事
I don't want to hear anything from you.
我对你的生意没兴趣
I don't care about your job.
此外…
And...
…我不想和你们有任何关联
...I want nothing to do with any of you.
我很抱歉这么说，但你们全都见鬼去吧
I beg your pardon, but you can all go to hell.
迪恩·基顿…
Dean Keaton...
…想正经做人
...gone the high road.
这世界是怎么了？
What is the world coming to?
去他的
Fuck him.
事情就是这么开始的:
And that was how it started:
我们五个因为莫须有的罪名
Five of us brought in on a trumped-up charge...
…被这些低能儿关了进来
...to be leaned on by half-wits.
在这儿我真不能多说
I really can't talk about it much here.
警察们永远也想不到的是…
What the cops never figured out, and what I know now...
…这些人永远不会屈服
...was that these men would never break, never lie down.
永远不会屈服于任何人
Never bend over for anybody.
任何人都不行
Anybody.
圣佩德罗  加利福尼亚  当日
- 你是谁？ - FBI探员 杰克·拜尔
- Who are you? - Agent Jack Baer, FBI.
- 死了多少人？ - 迄今为止发现15具尸体
- How many dead? - 15 so far.
还在继续打捞水下的尸体
They're still pulling bodies out of the water.
- 有生还者吗？ - 有两个
- Any survivors? - Two.
一个被送进了州立医院，但他正在昏迷中
One guy's in County hospital, but he's in a coma.
地方检察官带走了另一个家伙，一个跛脚的纽约人
The DA has a second guy, a cripple from New York.
上头下令封锁现场
The chief wants this place sealed off.
要是有别的问题， 就给他们电话吧
If you have any questions, give him a call.
我是奎恩，我去了洛杉矶，星期二才回来
This is Dave Kujan. I'll be in Los Angeles until Tuesday.
若有急事，可联系圣佩德罗警署的杰夫·拉宾…
If you need to reach me, contact Jeff Rabin of the San Pedro Police Department...
…找内线112即可，祝你顺利
...at extension 112. Have a nice day.
圣佩德罗警署  洛杉矶市
- 我为什么不能见他？ - 我已经说了…
- Why can't I see him? - I told you...
…地方检察官昨晚来这里
...the DA came down here last night ready to arraign...
…准备等他到了，就开始提审
...even before they moved him to County.
然后过了五分钟，肯特的律师露面了…
Kint's lawyer shows up five minutes later...
…地方检察官出来的时候，像是蔫了的茄子
...the DA comes out looking like the bogeyman smacked him around.
他们给他录了口供，并与他达成协议
They take his statement, and they cut him a deal.
- 他们以什么来起诉他？ - 非法持械，是轻罪
- Did they charge him with anything? - Weapons, misdemeanor 2.
究竟是怎么回事？
What is that?
这里的事情已经全部移交给地方检察官，明白吗？
I give the DA credit for getting that much, you understand?
请让一下
Excuse me, sir.
整件事情开始有政治色彩，市长昨晚来过了
This whole thing has turned political. The mayor was here last night.
今天早上州长也曾打电话给头儿
The chief. This morning, the governor called, okay?
我告诉你，这家伙的后台很硬
I'm telling you, this guy is protected from up on high by the Prince of Darkness.
- 记得我说的话吧 - 他什么时候可保释外出？
- Take my word for it. - When does he post bail?
- 可能最多再过两小时 - 我想要见见他
- Maybe two hours, tops. - I want to see him.
- 不行 - 我一定得见他
- No. - I gotta see him.
- 不，不行-- - 你得帮我
- No. I can't-- - You gotta do this for me.
我大老远来就是为了这事
I came a long way for this.
请进
Dave, please.
就算我让你见他，他也什么都不会说的
Even if I let you talk to him, he won't talk to you.
他会觉得是在被审问
He's paranoid about being recorded.
- 他知道审讯室里满布机关 - 我戒烟了
- He knows the rooms are wired. - I quit.
我不是审讯他，只不过随便谈谈罢了
This won't be an interrogation, just a friendly chat.
- 他不会进审讯室的 - 那就去别的地方
- He won't go into the interrogation room. - Then someplace else.
哪里呢？
Where?
不行，不行
No, no.
若这是毒品交易，那毒品呢？ 如果是谋杀，那又是谁指使的？
If this was a dope deal, where's the dope? If it was a hit, who called it?
我相信这些问题，在你心里已经有了答案
I'm sure you have a host of wild theories to answer all these questions.
- 你很清楚我的想法 - 这简直太疯狂了，而且也没什么意义
- You know what I think. - That's crazy, and it doesn't even matter.
这家伙根本不知情，他的背景也已经查出来了
The guy's got total immunity. His story checks out.
- 他没有你想知道的答案 - 我知道他没有答案
- He doesn't know what you want to know. - I don't think he does, not exactly.
但事情没有那么简单，相信我
But there's a lot more to his story, believe me.
我想知道码头上那二十七人的死因
I wanna know why 27 men died on that pier...
这事与九千一百万毒品有关，但现场竟找不到毒品
...for what looks to be $91 million worth of dope that wasn't there.
此外，我想确认迪恩·基顿的死讯
And above all, I want to be sure Dean Keaton's dead.
他确实死了
He's dead.
就给我两小时吧，到他被保释就结束
Come on. Two hours. Just till he makes bail.
他们都死了
They're all dead.
我才不在乎你说的，这个基顿有多厉害…
I don't care how tough you say Keaton was...
…船上没有生还的人
...nobody on that boat could've come out alive.
- 他能说话吗？ - 他醒来还不到一小时
- Is he talking? - He regained consciousness an hour ago.
说了些话，但不是英语，然后就停下了
He spoke, not English, then he lapsed.
- 是匈牙利语吗？ - 我不知道，也许是吧
- Hungarian? - That might have been it.
- 他们大部分是匈牙利人 - 你得把这穿上
- Most of them were Hungarians. - You gotta put this on.
烧伤病人很容易感染病菌
Burn victims are very susceptible to infection.
还有，那儿是禁烟的
And, of course, there's no smoking.
请戴上口罩，还有别去碰他
Keep your mask up. Please don't touch him.
他会死吗？
Is he gonna die?
他全身有六成被烧伤，肋骨断裂--
He's burned 60 percent of his body, broken ribs--
叫医院保安来，让人守在门口
Call security. Put a man on the door.
- 他会有危险？ - 对
- Is he dangerous? - Yes.
去吧
Do it.
快去
Do it now.
乔尔吗？我是拜尔，从洛杉矶给你打来的
Joel? Baer. Down at LA County.
他们在码头找到的那人，叫阿科西·卡瓦什
Look, the guy they pulled out of the harbor is Arkosh Kovash.
是的，我明白
Yes, I'm sure.
不，他受了重伤
No, he's all fucked up.
我听不清
I can't hear you.
闭会儿嘴好吗？我在打电话
Will you shut up? I'm on the phone.
对
Yes.
不，直到我派人来看着他
No, not till I put a man on him.
派个会说匈牙利语的人来
Send me someone who can speak Hungarian.
他已经醒了，这家伙说话就像个泰国妓女
He's awake. He's talking like a Thai hooker.
凯撒·苏斯
Keyser Soze.
- 什么？ - 凯撒·苏斯！
- What? - Keyser Soze!
这是怎么了？
No shit?
到法院去找丹·曼徹斯特
Call Dan Metzheiser over at Justice...
…还有海关的大卫·奎恩
...and find Dave Kujan from Customs.
维伯，这是海关的奎恩探员
Verbal, this is Agent Kujan from Customs.
幸会
Nice to meet you.
他想在你离开前问几个问题
He wants to ask you a few questions before you go.
- 什么问题？ - 大部分是关于迪恩·基顿的
- What about? - About a Dean Keaton, mostly.
但我想先从在纽约的指认谈起
I'd like to start at the lineup back in New York.
- 我能喝杯咖啡吗？ - 稍后再说吧，先说说指认时的事
- Can I get some coffee? - In a while. Let's talk about the lineup.
我真的很口渴，我就像小孩子那样容易脱水
I'm really thirsty. I used to dehydrate as a kid.
有次我尿出的小便就象鼻涕一样
Once I got so bad my piss come out like snot.
- 就是那种又浓又粘的-- - 我去给你弄咖啡
- It was all thick and gooey-- - I'll get your fucking coffee.
顺便帮我也冲一杯
Get me one, too, while you're at it.
那家伙太紧张了
That guy is tense.
紧张足以使人致命
Tension is a killer.
我曾经加入过在伊利诺州斯科基的一个男声四重唱组合
I used to be in a barbershop quartet in Skokie, Illinois.
男中音就叫基普·迪斯金， 是个超级大胖子
The baritone was this guy named Kip Diskin, big fat guy.
他每天早上都紧张的要命--
Like, orca fat. He was so stressed in the morning--
- 我们现在是想帮你 - 谢谢，我很感激
- You know we're trying to help you. - Sure, and I appreciate that.
我也想帮你，奎恩探员，我喜欢警察
And I wanna help you, Agent Kujan. I like cops.
我曾梦想成为联邦探员，可是我的--
I would've liked to have been a fed, but my CP--
你没对我们说实话，我知道你清楚一切
You're not tellin' us everything. I know you know something.
我已经对地方检察官全交待了
I told the DA everything I know.
我知道你喜欢基顿
I know you like Keaton.
- 我明白你认为他是好人 - 我知道他很好
- I know you think he's a good man. - I know he was good.
他曾是个贪污的警察
He was a corrupt cop.
对，15年前的事了，他还是个好贼
Sure. 15 years ago, but he was a good thief.
警察不会让他的行为合法化
The cops wouldn't let him go legit.
迪恩·基顿是垃圾
Dean Keaton was a piece of shit.
你想从我身上得到点什么？
Are you trying to get a rise out of me?
- 我只想听听你的故事 - 已经全说了
- I just wanna hear your story. - It's all there.
能抽支烟吗？
May I have a cigarette?
- 根据你的口供-- - 给个火
- According to your statement-- - I need a light.
根据你的口供，你只是个小毛贼…
According to your statement, you're a short-con operator...
…不入流的--
...run-of-the-mill--
根据你的口供，你只是个小毛贼…
According to your statement, you're a short-con operator...
…不入流的骗子
...run-of-the-mill scams.
这些口供应该已经被封存了
It's been suppressed. Anything in there is inadmissible.
我知道，你做了桩好交易，你已经被完全豁免
I know. Sweet deal you have here. Total immunity.
我因非法持枪罪被起诉，还有六个月的日子得熬
I do have the weapons charge. I'm lookin' at six whole months hard time.
认识一个叫鲁比·迪莫的商人吗？
You know a dealer named Ruby Deemer?
认识一个叫约翰·保罗的教徒吗？
You know a religious guy named John Paul?
- 知道阿提卡的鲁比吗？ - 我和他没什么瓜葛
- You know Ruby's in Attica? - He didn't have my lawyer.
我认识鲁比，他很受人尊敬
I know Ruby. He's big on respect.
他是我的好朋友，也很喜欢我
He's a good friend of mine, likes me very much.
我知你的证供已被封存，可鲁比交游广阔
I know your testimony is sealed. Ruby's well connected.
有许多朋友愿为他效力
He's got lots of friends inside who do favors for him.
如果他知道你把他的名字供给了地方检察官，知道他会怎么做吗？
What would he say if he found out you dropped his name to the DA?
- 上面根本没提鲁比的事 - 可我会这么对他说
- There's nothing there on Ruby. - I'll be sure to mention that to him.
知道我从这行学了什么？ 就是如何认出凶手
Know what I've learned on the job? How to spot a murderer.
假设捉了宗谋杀案的三个疑犯
Say you arrest three guys for the same killing.
你把他们关通宵
Put them in jail overnight.
到了第二天早上，谁要是睡着了，谁就是凶手
Next morning, whoever's sleeping is your man.
如果你犯了罪，等到被捕，你的戒心就松懈了
If you're guilty, you know you're caught. You let your guard down.
- 明白吗？ - 不
- You follow me? - No.
让我开门见山的直说
Let me get to the point.
我比你聪明， 我会查出我要知的事
I'm smarter than you, and I'm gonna find out what I wanna know.
无论你是否喜欢，我都会查出真相
I'll get it, whether you like it or not.
我也不是鼠辈
I'm not a rat.
谢谢
Thanks.
我曾在危地马拉尝过咖啡豆磨的新鲜咖啡
When I was pickin' beans in Guatemala we used to make fresh coffee.
直接从树上摘下的那种，好喝极了
Right off the trees, I mean. That was good.
- 这味道糟透了，谁让我是在警察局里呢  - 能继续吗？
- This is shit, but I'm in a police station. - Can we get started again?
指认结束后怎样了？
What happened after the lineup?
那值班的对我说不能保释你
The desk sergeant was telling me he couldn't release you.
你能相信吗？你甚至未被起诉
Can you believe that? You weren't even charged.
该死的警察
Damn police.
我要给你的脸拍照
I wanna have pictures taken of your face.
-明天就送到地方检察官那儿 - 算了吧
- I'll take them to the DA tomorrow. - Forget about it.
星期一我就会把这事报到大陪审团去
I'll have this thing in front of a grand jury by Monday.
我不想再谈这事了
I don't want to talk about it, okay?
弗提和雷诺那边怎么说？
What did Fortier and Renault say?
他们需要多些时间考虑投资
They asked for more time to think about investing.
该死的
Damn it.
需要多些时间干什么？
More time for what?
无论你怎么掩饰我的过去，他们还是会查到我的底细
No matter how you cover my tracks they're still gonna find out about me.
相信我
Give me some credit.
我会帮你澄清的，我们一起去庭内合议
I got you this far. Let's go to the grand jury.
- 如果不这样，这事不会停-- - 这事永远不会停
- This isn't gonna stop if we don't-- - It's never going to stop, period.
下星期所有投资者都将抛弃我们
By next week, every investor in the city is gonna be walking away from us.
完了
It's finished.
我徹底完了
I'm finished.
别轻言放弃，基顿
Don't give up on me now.
这事永远也不会停
It's never gonna stop.
我爱你
I love you.
他们今晚毁了我
They ruined me in there tonight.
我爱你
I love you.
你听到了吗？
Do you hear me?
什么？
What?
好了
All right.
去我家吧
Let's just go to my place.
明天再想这些烦事
We'll worry about this tomorrow.
走吧
Let's go.
范斯特和麦克麦纳斯有个很好的计划:
Fenster and McManus had a cagey proposition:
钱来的快，风险高，利润也大
A fast-jump, high-risk, long money.
我们都知道那行得通
We all knew it could be done.
我想那事若是办坏了就得杀人
The way I figured, to do it wrong meant killing.
可要办好就要集齐五个人
To do it right took five men.
五个人的关键就是基顿
Five men meant Keaton.
基顿总是令人信服的
Keaton took convincing.
纽约警察出租公司
New York's finest taxi service.
胡说
Bullshit.
他们早就已经不干了
They don't operate anymore.
麦克麦纳斯有个朋友在十四区，他们星期四收到了风声
McManus has a friend in the 14th precinct. They're coming out for one job, Thursday.
他们准备收拾一个从南非走私宝石的家伙
They're pickin' up a guy smuggling emeralds from South America.
麦克麦纳斯已经找到了销赃人
McManus already has a fence set up.
- 销赃人？是谁？ - 是个加州人，叫雷德福特
- A fence? Who? - Some guy in California called Redfoot.
- 我从未听说过这家伙 - 你一定要来
- I never heard of him. - You have to come.
- 我来与不来，与你何干？ - 他们不认识我，只认识你
- What's it to you whether I do it or not? - They don't know me. You do.
除非你一起干，否则他们不信我
They won't take me unless you go.
替我想想，我需要这笔钱
Look at me. I need this.
难道你就不需要？这是你家吗？
You're telling me you don't need this? Is this your place?
我不是在打击你，难道你就打算跟着这律师吃软饭？
I'm not knocking you. You got a good scam going with this lawyer.
对不起
Sorry.
算了
It's okay.
你说得不错
You say it's the real thing? That's cool.
你没事吧？
You okay?
我已经洗手不干
I was out of line.
可他们仍不放过我们，你很明白这点
But they're never gonna stop with us. You know that.
即使像你般清白，他们仍缠着你
As clean as you get, they'll never let you go now.
这么干，既能给警察们颜色看， 同时我们也得了好处
This way, we hit the cops where it hurts, and we get well in the meantime.
你真的没事吗？
You sure you're okay?
会没事的
I'll be all right.
你看…
Look, I...
- …我有时候-- - 别说了
- ...sometimes get-- - Forget it.
我今晚可能会泻血
I'll probably shit blood tonight.
那么…
So...
…他们想怎么下手？
...how do they wanna do it?
麦克麦纳斯想开杀戒，可我反对
McManus wants to go in shooting. I say no.
范斯特呢？哈肯尼呢？
Fenster? Hockney?
他们都豁出去了，什么都干的出来
They're pretty pissed off. They'll do anything.
我有条不用杀任何人的路
I got a way to do it without killing anyone.
可就像我说的，没有你，他们不会让我加入
But like I say, they won't let me in without you.
三百万？
$3 million?
也许更多
Maybe more.
不杀人
No killing.
只要依我的方法行事便成
Not if we do it my way.
纽约警察出租车公司是个地下称呼
New York's finest taxi service was not your normal taxi service.
那是纽约贪污警察的生财工具…
It was a ring of corrupt cops in the NYPD that ran a high-profit racket...
…他们接载走私客和毒贩
...driving smugglers and drug dealers all over the city.
付上每公里三百元的价钱，你就有了私人的蓝白警察卫队
For $300 a mile, you got your own blue and white...
他们甚至还备有名片
...and a police escort. They even had their own business cards.
没过多久，有人提出了质询，而这计程车服务亦告终结
After a while, somebody started asking questions, and the taxi service shut down.
随后内政部的人将涉案的人都拘捕了
Ever since then, Internal Affairs has been waiting to catch them in the act.
我们就对那伙人下手
That's where we came in.
- 旅程愉快吗？ - 好的很
- So, how was the flight? - Fuckin' great.
用这车能送我去斯坦顿岛吗？
Will this get me to Staten Island?
开什么玩笑？ 就是把你送到科德角去也行
Are you kiddin' me? This will get you to Cape Cod.
麦克麦纳斯去接生意，范斯特安排车辆
McManus came to us with the job. Fenster got the vans.
哈肯尼提供枪械
Hockney supplied the hardware.
我则想办法不让人被杀
I came through with how to do it so no one got killed.
基顿？基顿把整件事添上最后一笔
But Keaton? Keaton put on the finishing touch.
稍有差错，我们五人将落到警方手上
A little "fuck you" from the five of us to the NYPD.
看着点
Watch this.
小心
Careful.
真该死
Come on, asshole!
天啊！
Holy shit!
- 别动，混蛋！ - 把枪放下，杂种！
- Don't move, you fucker! - Drop it now, motherfucker!
把他妈的枪丢掉！快丢掉！
Drop the fuckin' gun! Drop it!
别他妈的碰任何东西
Don't fuckin' touch a fuckin' thing.
- 你们想要干什么？ - 把那该死的东西拿开
- What do you guys want? - Put your fuckin' thing away.
我们是警察，蠢货！
We're cops! Stupid assholes!
- 小心玻璃！ - 别动，杂种！
- Watch the glass! - Don't fuckin' move, motherfucker!
- 想尝颗子弹吗？胖子 - 闭嘴！
- You want a buckshot shampoo, chubby? - Shut up!
他妈的
Fuck.
下午好，兄弟，把东西给我
'Afternoon, my little pork chops. Give me the shit.
- 别动！ - 把那东西给他！
- Don't move! - Give him the shit!
快把那该死的东西给他！
Give him the fuckin' thing!
Give him the fuckin' shit, man!
快点！拿来！
Hurry up! Come on!
- 还有钱 - 没有钱了
- Now the money! - There's no money.
- 把钱交出来！ - 根本没有钱
- Give me the money now! - There's no fuckin' money.
把钱给他！
Give him the fuckin' money!
- 快！把钱给他！ - 把钱给我！
- Do it! Give him the money! - Give me the money!
- 把钱给他！ - 快点！
- Give him the money! - Hurry up!
你们知道我是谁吗？
You know who the fuck I am?
你们这些家伙知道我是谁吗？ 他妈的！
You people know who the fuck I am? Fuck!
现在知道了
We do now, jerk-off.
混蛋
Cocksucker.
等等，那算什么？
Wait a minute. What's that?
这到底算什么？
What the fuck?
天啊！
Holy shit!
走！
Go!
基顿打了个匿名电话
Keaton made an anonymous phone call.
新闻界与警察一起抵达现场
The press was on the scene before the police were.
三日后，施特劳斯和瑞兹被起诉
Strausz and Rizzi were indicted three days later.
不到几个星期，又有50多个警察也被起诉
Within a few weeks, 50 more cops went down with them.
这案子牵连很广，直到挖出了他们的头脑
Everybody got it right in the ass, from the chief on down.
干的漂亮极了
It was beautiful.
我欠你两块半
I owe you $2.50.
基顿博士
Dr.Keaton.
- 比我想的要多 - 销赃的家伙什么时候到？
- There's more here than I thought. - When's the fence coming?
雷德福特不会主动来见我，一般都是我去找他
Redfoot never comes to see me. I always go to see him.
在加州？
In California?
是的，维伯，在加州           范斯特和我--
Yes, Verbal, in California. Fenster and I--
等等，先收声，你和范斯特？不行
Wait, hold the fuckin' phone. You and Fenster? No.
- 你们想耍我？ - 那么派谁去？
- You fuckin' kiddin' me? - So then, who's gonna go?
我们一起去
We all go.
你有什么问题吗？伙计
What's your fuckin' problem, man?
我的问题就是，你和范斯特会在加州逍遥快活
My problem, is you and Fenster honeymooning in California...
…而把我们甩在这里提心吊胆
...while the rest of us are sittin' here holding our dicks.
已经完事了
The job's over.
冷静点
Cool it.
洛杉矶是个轻松的好地方
LA's a good place to lay low for a while.
想要跳舞吗？
You wanna dance?
变态
Ladies.
我提议大家干一杯
I would like to propose a toast.
敬你的
There you go.
为足智多谋的…
To Mr.Verbal...
…“口水先生”而干
...the man with the plan.
我们会错过班机的
We're gonna miss the flight.
别傻等了，给她留张便条就行了
Don't do this. Send her a note. Something.
我说了来得及的
I said we'll make it.
我们快要误机了
We're gonna miss the plane.
她会理解的
She'll understand.
那真的很感人
That's heartwarming. Really.
我有点想哭了
I'm weepy.
到外面去等好吗？
You wanna wait outside?
是你们想知道发生的事，我正和你们说实话
You guys wanted to know what happened. I'm telling you.
继续吧，维伯
Come on, Verbal.
你以为我是谁？你要我相信他真会洗手不干？
Who do you think you're talkin' to? You expect me to believe that he retired?
就为了个女人？
For a woman?
胡扯，基顿是在利用她
Bullshit. Keaton was using her.
- 他爱他 - 没错
- He loved her. - Sure.
我很难相信袭击出租车，不是他的主意
I'm supposed to believe that hitting the taxi service wasn't his idea.
- 是范斯特和麦克麦纳斯提出的 - 基顿做了四年的警察
- It was all Fenster and McManus. - Keaton was a cop for four years.
谁会比他知道的更清楚？
Who else would know better?
- 他已经是臭名远扬 - 但伊迪使他全改变了
- That job had his name on it. - Edie had him turned around.
让我这么告诉你吧
Let me tell you something.
我了解迪恩·基顿
I know Dean Keaton.
过去四年我一直在调查他
I've been investigating him for the past three years.
我知道这家伙是个冷血的杂种
The guy I know was a cold-blooded bastard.
警队开除他前，已有三次被控谋杀
IAD indicted him on three counts of murder before he was kicked off the force.
别告诉我妓女也有颗金子般的心
Don't sell me the hooker with a heart of gold.
你完全误会了他
You got him all wrong.
是吗？
Do I?
迪恩·基顿在警队时，已有七次被控罪的记录
Dean Keaton was under indictment seven times while he was on the force.
每次不是证人翻供
In every case, witnesses either reversed their testimony...
…就是在出庭前就被干掉
...or died before they could testify.
等到终于能把他入罪，并送进州立新新监狱关上五年
When they finally did nail him for fraud, he spent five years in Sing Sing.
他却在里面杀了三个囚犯
He killed three prisoners inside.
当然，我不能证明此事
Of course, I can't prove this...
…但我亦不能证明他没有做
...but I can't prove the best part either.
迪恩·基顿死过一次
Dean Keaton was dead.
你知道那故事吗？
Did you know that?
两年前他在调查一宗…
He died in a fire two years ago, during an investigation into the murder...
…证人被杀案时葬身火海
...of a witness who was going to testify against him.
有两人见到迪恩·基顿在爆炸前进了货仓
Two people saw Dean Keaton walk into a warehouse he owned...just before it blew up.
他们说他去检查煤气是否泄漏
They said he went in to check a leaking gas main.
结果迪恩·基顿就此葬身火海
It blew up and took all of Dean Keaton with it.
爆炸发生三个月后，那两个目击者也死了
Within three months of the explosion, the two witnesses, they were dead.
一个是在车内自杀
One killed himself in his car.
另一个从电梯跌下而死
The other fell down an open elevator shaft.
让我们快开始吧
Let's get this show on the road.
我们说好了不能这样，现在有太多--
This is not what we discussed. There are too many--
我答应他死之前我们会离开
I promise we'll be out before he blows his porch light.
- 我中午还有会要开 - 只能待五分钟
- I have a noon meeting. - Five minutes.
好，所有人要冷静点
Everyone calm down, all right?
我要你问他码头枪战的事
I want you to ask this man about the shootout in the harbor.
- 他说他们在买-- - 是毒品，我们知道
- He says they were buying-- - Dope. We know.
他不知道他们要买什么，但肯定不是毒品
He doesn't know what they were buying, but not dope.
- 是人 - 什么？
- People. - What?
他需要保证…
He needs guarantees...
- 他说什么？保证？ - 他说他有生命危险
- What is he talking about, guarantees? - He says his life is in danger.
他见到有只魔鬼在望着他
He saw the Devil. Looked him in the eye.
- 我得走了 - 不，再等等
- I'm on my way. - No, wait a minute.
问他那个他说过的…
Ask him to tell him what he told me...
…那个魔鬼的事
...about the Devil.
魔鬼是谁？
Who's the Devil?
凯撒·苏斯
Keyser Soze.
凯撒·苏斯？
Keyser Soze?
他在码头上杀了许多人
He was in the harbor, killing many men.
他看见了凯撒·苏斯？
He saw Keyser Soze?
- 他看到了他的脸 - 好，好
- He saw his face. - All right.
让他告诉她，那人的长相是怎样的
Tell him to tell her what he looks like.
形容出来
Describe him.
六星期前，我接到匿名电话…
Six weeks ago, I get an anonymous phone call...
…说能在蒙第诺餐厅找到基顿，事实上他确实在
...telling me I can find Keaton eating at Mondino's, and there he is.
由于他伪称已死并没什么利益
Because he never profited from his alleged death...
…也因为我们已找到真正的凶手
...and we convicted someone else of the murder we tried to pin on him...
…所以只得让他走
...we had to let him go.
他伪称死去的时间已经够长，足以平息那宗谋杀案的影响
He was dead just long enough for the murder rap to blow over.
于是他就开始露面吃午餐了
And then he had lunch.
我对那一无所知
I don't know about that.
我不认为你知道什么，可你说看见基顿死了
I don't think you do, but you say you saw Keaton die.
我在想你可能是为他掩饰，而他仍藏身在某处
I think you're covering his ass, and he's still out there.
我认为他就是码头枪战的幕后主使
I think he's behind that circus at the harbor.
他利用你是因为你笨，而且认为自己是他的朋友
My bet is he's using you because you're stupid and think he's your friend.
你对我说他已死，就当他死了
You tell me he's dead, so be it.
我只想在回纽约前确定他已死
I wanna be sure before I go back to New York.
他根本不是幕后主使，那是个律师
He wasn't behind anything. It was the lawyer.
什么律师？
What lawyer?
在我还在男声四重唱组时--
Back when I was in that barbershop quartet--
你以为我不知道，你隐瞒了地方检察官？
You don't think I know you held out on the DA?
你到底隐瞒了什么？
What did you leave out?
我能在十分钟内就找到鲁比
I could be on the phone to Ruby in 10 minutes.
- 地方检察官已经将我豁免 - 我还没有
- The DA gave me immunity. - Not from me.
我并没有豁免你，混蛋
You get no immunity from me, you piece of shit.
我将所有罪犯关在狱中，每个警察都感激我…
Every criminal I have put in prison, every cop that owes me a favor...
…所有犯罪的大小角色…
...every creep and scumbag that walks the street...
…都会知道维伯·肯特的大名…
...will know the name of Verbal Kint. You talk to me...
…你给我老实交待，不然你获得的珍贵豁免权…
...or that precious immunity they grant you...
…绝不会交到你手上
...won't be worth the paper the contract put out on your life is printed on.
还有个律师
There was a lawyer.
叫小林
Kobayashi.
- 就是他杀了基顿？ - 不是，但我肯定基顿已经死了
- Is he the one that killed Keaton? - No, but I'm sure Keaton is dead.
说服我相信
Convince me.
把详情原原本本说出来
Tell me every last detail.
我们抵达洛杉矶去会麦克麦纳斯的销赃人，雷德福特
We arrived in Los Angeles and met McManus' fence, Redfoot.
他有着不错的名声，似乎是个好人
He had a good reputation. Seemed like a good guy.
- 可我们还得多了解 - 还好吗？
- Still, we should have known better. - How you doing?
- 还好，你呢？ - 也不坏，马马虎虎了
- Good. You? - Not bad. Can't complain.
你怎么样，范斯特？
How's it going, Fenster?
不需要打开吧？
Don't need to open it, right?
你一定是基顿
You must be Keaton.
这是雷德福特，这是迪恩·基顿
Redfoot, Dean Keaton.
- 托德·霍克尼，还有维伯·肯特.  - 计谋多多的维伯？
- Todd Hockney and Verbal Kint. - Verbal, the man with the plan.
有兴趣再干一把吗？
You interested in more work?
- 我们一直在找活干 - 我们在休假
- We're always looking for extra work. - We're on vacation.
那真可惜
That's too bad.
我有大堆的活，可惜就是找不到好手
I got a ton of work and no good people.
- 要像你们这般身手的 - 有什么活？
- Not like you guys. - What's the job?
有个从德克萨斯州来的珠宝商，叫索尔
There's this jeweler out of Texas named Saul.
他在市中心的酒店租了间套房
He rents a suite in some downtown hotel.
他免费为人鉴定价格，有时会买，有时却不买
He does free appraisals. Sometimes he buys, sometimes he doesn't.
简而言之，他手上有大笔现金
The word is, he carries around a lot of cash.
我想的就是，我可以收货，而你拿现钞
So I figure, I keep the merchandise, you keep the green.
- 简单的很 - 安全方面如何？
- Simple. - What about security?
有两个保镖，你们完全可以搞定
A couple of bodyguards. Nothing you couldn't handle.
可以给我时间考虑吗？
Give me time to check it out?
我从来不会对你失望，兄弟
I expect nothing less from you, man.
很高兴见到你，电话联系吧
Good to see you. We'll call you.
好好的在洛杉矶享受
Enjoy LA. Get yourself laid.
有个纽约朋友告诉我，你认识斯伯克·霍利斯
A friend in New York tells me that you knew Spook Hollis.
我听说你曾和他一同服过刑
The way I hear it, you did time with ol' Spook.
他是个好人
A good man, wasn't he?
我以前曾为他贩过毒
I used to run dope for him.
可惜挂了
Too bad he got shivved.
是我把他干掉的
I shivved him.
这事直接由我告诉你，总比以后别人传给你好
Better you hear it from me now than from somebody else later.
谢谢你告诉我
I appreciate that.
恕我好奇…
But just out of curiosity...
这纯粹是公事，抑或私人问题？
...was it business or personal?
两者都是
A bit of both.
就如我说的…
Like I said...
…若你有兴趣，可给我电话
...you give me a call if you're interested.
有问题吗？
Is there a problem?
只干一次
One job.
就是这样
That was the deal.
只干一次？
One job?
说的真好
That's a good one.
基顿已经竭尽所能，但人不能改变身份
Keaton fought it as best he could, but a man can't change what he is.
他可对人说他另一个身份，但始终不能摆脱自己
He can convince anyone he's someone else, but never himself.
麦克麦纳斯整天都在唠叨，于是我们又干回本行
It took one day with McManus nagging, and we went back to work.
于是我下了车，那事全被搅了
I get out of my car, and the thing is wrecked.
我向另外那辆车的后座看去，那女人几乎全脱光了
I look in the backseat of the other car, and this woman's totally naked.
- 我笑到快透不过气来   - 上车吧，索尔
- I'm laughin' so hard I can't breathe. - Get in the car, Saul.
- 别动，混蛋！ - 站着别动！
- Freeze, motherfucker! - Stay right there!
那边还有一个人
There's a second one here, somewhere.
把公文箱给我，快把公文箱给我！
Gimme the case. Give me the fuckin' case!
快把公文箱给我，我讲最后一次…
Give me the fuckin' case. I'm tellin' you for the last time.
快把公文箱给我！
Give me the fuckin' case!
- 过来！ - 别动！
- Come on! - Don't move!
把箱子递出来
Hand over the case.
给我把箱子递出来
Hand over the fuckin' case.
好了，走吧！
Come on, let's go!
- 快！ - 今天真倒霉
- Come on! - Bad day. Fuck it.
快走了！
Let's go!
混蛋
Fuck.
- 就像是堆泥巴般毫无价值 - 真该死
- Looks like a lot of china to me. - Shit.
伙计们，来了
Guys, come on.
- 你想干什么？ - 我要杀了那家伙
- What are you doin'? - I'm gonna kill him.
我们已经按你的方式错了回，现在听我的
We did it your way, now we'll do it mine.
- 你要杀他吗？ - 我去和他谈
- You gonna kill him? - I'll deal with him.
- 你最好和他好好谈谈 - 闭嘴
- You'd better, or I'm gonna. - Shut up.
你叫我拿这东西有什么用？
What am I supposed to do with that?
拿来喂那跛子吧，能帮他止痛，我也对此不知情
Feed it to the gimp. Ease his pain. I don't know what that is.
- 什么意思？ - 我并不知情
- What do you mean? - I don't know.
是个律师叫我这么做的
I got thrown this job by some lawyer.
是谁？
Who?
我不知道，是个英国佬
I don't know. Some limey.
他也只是个中间人，他没有说，我也没问
He's a middleman for somebody. He doesn't say, I don't ask.
- 你真是个混蛋！ - 去死吧！
- You're fuckin' full of shit! - Fuck you.
- 你才去死吧！ - 听我说
- Fuck you. - Listen to me.
我们想要见他
We wanna meet him, okay?
那真巧了
That's funny.
昨晚他给我电话，也说想要见你们
He called me last night. He says he wants to meet you guys.
那好，我们去见他
Okay, we'll meet him.
- 我会给你电话 - 好，我们走
- I'll call you. - Good. Let's go.
我不想这样，等等，还有件事，坏小子:
I don't like it. Wait a minute. One more thing, tough guy:
再玩什么花样，我会做了你
Any more surprises, and I'm gonna kill you.
就当帮我个忙好吗？
You're such a tough guy. But do me a favor, all right?
快在我面前消失
Get the fuck off my dick.
不要！
No!
好好管教管教那小子
Put a leash on that puppy.
索尔被杀真是糟糕透了
It's an awful shame about Saul gettin' whacked.
警察在追缉凶徒
Cops'll be lookin' for the guys who did it.
他们迟早会来问我
Sooner or later, they're gonna come around askin' me.
祝你们晚安，小姐们
You have a sweet night, ladies.
去死吧
Fuck you.
- 那么这个律师-- - 小林
- So this lawyer-- - Kobayashi.
- 是雷德福特引来的？ - 对
- Came from Redfoot. - Right.
和地方检察官说的时候为何漏了这段？
And why leave this out when you talked to the DA?
大卫，有人找你
Dave, someone to see you.
我满世界的在找你
I've been looking all over for you.
仍在追查昨晚码头大屠杀的毒品？
You still after that coke that took a walk out of that bloodbath yesterday?
不用查了，根本没有毒品
You can stop looking. There was no coke.
我去州立医院找了那个从下水道救上的…
I've been in LA County talking to a guy they pulled out of a drainpipe...
…昨晚枪战后的幸存者
...yesterday after the shootout.
今早他苏醒了，并说了些事情
He came to this morning, he started talking.
他是匈牙利匪帮的一员，他们预备和阿根廷党徒交易
He's part of a Hungarian mob. They dealt with gwats from Argentina.
他说这事与毒品交易无关
He says it was definitely not a dope deal.
- 但是-- - 我知道，可他说这事与毒品无关
- But there were-- - We know. But he says no on the dope.
这匈牙利人告诉我 这班人第二天便要去土耳其
This Hungarian tells me they were pulling stumps for Turkey the next day.
他们没时间去讨论那批货，也没考虑搬它
They had no time for that kind of product, and no means to move it.
- 那钱是做什么的？ - 他不知道
- What's the money for? - He didn't know.
除了几个关键人物外，无人知晓
No one doing the deal knew except for a few key people.
他说那些人都守口如瓶
They were all very hush about it, he says.
- 无论那是什么，都牵连重大 - 我不太明白
- Whatever it was, it was very sensitive. - I don't get it.
你见到了那个跛脚的纽约人吗？
You got the cripple in there from New York?
他有提到凯撒·苏斯没？
Did he mention Keyser Soze?
谁？
Who?
请原谅我的打扰
Just bear with me here.
- 谁是凯撒·苏斯？ - 去死吧！
- Who's Keyser Soze? - Fuck!
我们已经争论了一个半小时
We've been goin' over this for an hour and a half.
我们只需要做了雷德福特，然后离开这该死的地方就行
What we need to do is find Redfoot and get the hell out of here now.
我们需要先思考周全
What we need to do is think.
再想想
Think back.
有人有能力…
Somebody with power...
…有人能从纽约 一直追查我们到这里
...somebody capable of tracking us from New York to LA.
- 那我们在这儿做什么？ - 我们得等待
- What the hell are we doing here? - We're waiting.
- 坐下    - 不用了，我火气大着，他妈烦透了
- Sit down. - No. I'm hot, and I'm fuckin' bored.
哈肯尼先生，停下
Mr.Hockney, do stay.
基顿先生
Mr.Keaton.
范斯特先生，我赏识他的枪法…
Mr.Fenster I recognize from his mug shots...
…就和麦克麦纳斯的一样好
...as well as Mr.McManus.
你一定就是肯特先生，那位干掉索尔伯格的人
I can only assume that you are Mr.Kint, the gentleman who disposed of Saul Berg.
我的雇主致上他的感谢和一份意想不到的礼物
My employer sends his gratitude, a most unexpected benefit.
我就是小林先生
I am Mr.Kobayashi.
我的雇主要我带份建议书来
I have been asked by my employer to bring a proposal to you gentlemen.
-你想怎样？ -我雇主想你们为他效劳
- What do you want? - My employer requires your services.
任务只得一个，工作一天，但相当危险
One job, one day's work. Very dangerous.
他没预计你们全部能活命…
He does not expect all of you to live. But those of you who do...
…但能活命的可将那九千一百万分了
...will have $91 million to divide between you in any way you see fit.
谁是你的老板？
Who's your boss?
我为凯撒·苏斯做事
I work for Keyser Soze.
谁是凯撒·苏斯？
Who's Keyser Soze?
你太情绪化了，肯特先生
Judging by the sudden change in mood...
…我想你的合伙人也是这么认为的
...I feel sure the rest of your associates can tell you.
我代苏斯先生向你们提出建议
I come with an offer directly from Mr.Soze.
- 实际上是个命令 - 什么叫做“命令”？
- An order, actually. - What do you mean, "an order"?
1981年，你在纽约巴弗洛区抢劫货车
In 1981, you participated in the hijacking of a truck in Buffalo, New York.
车上是原钢材料，这批材料原属于苏斯先生…
The cargo was raw steel, steel which belonged to Mr.Soze...
…本应送到巴基斯坦作核反应堆
...and which was destined for Pakistan to be used in a nuclear reactor.
那是违反联合国条例的大生意
A most profitable violation of UN Regulations.
你根本不知此事，基顿先生
You had no way of knowing this...
因为帮苏斯先生承运的人
...because the fellow shipping the steel was working for Soze...
也根本毫不知情
...without his knowledge.
今年初，范斯特先生与麦克麦纳斯先生…
Earlier this year, Mr.Fenster and Mr.McManus...
在纽华克机场抢劫了架双座货机
...hijacked a two-prop cargo flight out of Newark airport.
机上载有黄金和白金
The plane was carrying gold and platinum wiring also set for Pakistan.
两个月前，哈肯尼先生偷了…
Two months ago, Mr.Hockney stole a truck...
…途经皇后区的装载枪械零件的货车
...carrying gun parts through Queens.
而这些枪支零件本要由纽约州政府监督销毁
Gun parts which were set to be destroyed by the state of New York.
但在贝尔法斯特转机时就失踪了
They were to be lost in a way station and rerouted to Belfast.
同样地，苏斯先生利用不知情的人
Again, Mr.Soze using pawns who had no knowledge.
这样我们就找到了肯特先生
Which brings us to Mr.Kint.
九个月前，苏斯先生的…
Nine months ago, one of Mr.Soze's...
…一个不算聪明的手下
...less than intelligent couriers was taken in a complicated confidence scam...
…被一个跛子所骗
...by a cripple.
他被骗去了六万二千元
He was relieved of $62,000.
花了很长时间，我们才找齐你们
Now, it has taken us some time to find you.
我们想你们在纽约落网后再找你们
Our intention was to approach you after your apprehension in New York.
是你安排的指认过程
You set up the lineup.
是的，我不来，你们是不会被释放的
Yes. You were not to be released until I had come to see you.
看来基顿先生的律师菲娜琳小姐
It seems Mr.Keaton's attorney, Miss Finneran...
…做事很有效率
...was a little too effective in expediting his release.
他比你们其他人出狱快多了
Holding the rest of you became a moot point.
- 那雷德福特呢？ - 雷德福特先生也一无所知
- What about Redfoot? - Mr.Redfoot knew nothing.
苏斯先生很少长时间用同一批人工作
Mr.Soze rarely works with the same people for long...
而工作的人也不知道在为谁效劳
...and they never know who they're working for.
如果没有手下，就不会被出卖
One cannot be betrayed if one has no people.
你为什么告诉我们？
So, why are you telling us?
因你们偷了苏斯先生的东西
Because you have stolen from Mr.Soze, Mr.Fenster.
你们所有人
All of you.
由于你们不知道偷的东西是他的，所以你们还活着
That you did not know it is the only reason you're still alive.
他觉得是你们欠了他，你们要还债给他
He feels you owe him. You will repay your debt.
去他妈的债，你去死吧，我们怎么知道你是为苏斯工作？
Fuck the debt, and fuck you. How do we know you work for Soze?
这有关系吗，哈肯尼先生？
I don't think that is very relevant.
你们五个与索尔·伯格…
All five of you are responsible for the murder of Saul Berg...
…及其保镖的死有关
...and his bodyguards.
雷德福特先生可证明此事
Mr.Redfoot can testify to your involvement.
我们知道他会这么做的
We can see to it that he will.
- 你想说什么？ - 建议是这样的:
- What's your point? - The offer is this, gentlemen:
苏斯先生一直对毒品生意
Mr.Soze's primary interest...
…很有兴趣
...is narcotics.
他与阿根廷党竞争数年之久
He has been competing, shall we say...with a group of Argentineans for several years.
与苏斯先生对抗的人，已经尝到了教训
Competing with Mr.Soze has taken its toll.
他们三天前商谈好了一宗…
These Argentineans are negotiating the sale...
…九千一百万元的可卡因买卖
...of $91 million in cocaine in three days time.
不用说，这笔交易将重新复活他们的组织
Needless to say, this purchase will revitalize...the diminishing strength of their organization.
苏斯先生想让你们制止这次买卖
Mr.Soze would like you to stop the deal.
你们可等交易完成后才动手
If you choose, you may wait until after the buy.
他们交易的钱全属于你们
Whatever money changes hands is yours.
苏斯先生想你们在船上销毁那些可卡因
Mr.Soze would like you to get to the boat and destroy the cocaine onboard.
此后你们就与他两不相欠
And then you will be free of your obligations to Mr.Soze.
给个好理由，好让我现在不杀你
Give me one good reason why I shouldn't kill you right now.
这是苏斯先生给你们的礼物
A gift from Mr.Soze.
再见，先生们
Good day, gentlemen.
他们知道我以前的一切，我18岁后干过的一切
They got my whole life in here, everything I've done since I was 18.
他们什么都知道
They fuckin' know everything.
甚至知道以前曾与我一同做牢的人
Everybody I've ever worked with or did time with.
不
No.
- 这事不对劲   - 我不知道
- This isn't right. - I don't know.
纽约常提及苏斯的人是谁？
Who's that guy who used to talk about Soze in New York?
- 是布里克·马林 - 他间接为他做事
- Bricks Marlin. - He did jobs for him, indirect stuff.
他常说他所做的事有五倍利润
He said he always made five times more money on it than the job was worth.
那人是幻想狂
This guy's a pipe dream.
小林利用他作掩护
Kobayashi's using him for window dressing.
我不知道，这糟透了
I don't know. This is bad.
都是鬼扯，这人可能是纽约警察，这根本就是个圈套
It's bullshit. This guy could be LAPD. It's a fuckin' setup.
我听说的苏斯是个屠夫
The way I hear it, Soze's some kind of butcher.
- 是个变态无比的屠夫 - 根本没有凯撒·苏斯这人！
- A peerless, psycho, fucked-up butcher. - There is no Keyser Soze!
凯撒·苏斯是谁？
Who is Keyser Soze?
他应该是个土耳其人，有人说他父亲是德国人
He's supposed to be Turkish. Some say his father was German.
人人都认为他是虚构的
Nobody ever believed he was real.
从来没有人亲眼见过他
Nobody knew him or saw anybody that ever worked directly for him.
据小林说，任何人都可能为苏斯卖命
To hear Kobayashi tell it, anybody could have worked for Soze.
没人会知道，这就是他厉害之处
You never knew. That was his power.
最巧妙之处就是还能让人相信他不存在
The greatest trick the Devil ever pulled...was convincing the world he didn't exist.
那些家伙告诉我一个故事
One story the guys told me, the story I believe
我想那是他在土耳其时发生的事
...was from his days in Turkey.
有班匈牙利人想建立自己的组织
There was a gang of Hungarians that wanted their own mob.
他们知道想拥有权力…
They realized that to be in power, you didn't need guns...
…不用枪械，金钱， 甚至不需要手下
...or money or even numbers.
你只需做其他人不敢做的事
You just needed the will to do what the other guy wouldn't.
不久，他们努力做大，成为仅次于苏斯的另一大势力
After a while they come into power, and then they come after Soze.
他当时势力不大，只是经营毒品
He was small-time then. Just running dope, they say.
一天下午，他们到他家找他麻烦
They come to his home...in the afternoon looking for his business.
但只在家里找到他妻儿，于是决定等苏斯回来
They find his wife and kids in the house, and decide to wait for Soze.
苏斯回家见妻子被奸，孩子们在哭喊
He comes home to find his wife raped and children screaming.
匈牙利人知道苏斯不好对付，都不敢惹他
The Hungarians knew Soze was tough, not to be trifled with.
他们告诉他只是想谈生意
They let him know they meant business.
不！
No!
他们说想要他的地盘，以及他所有业务
They tell him they want his territory, all his business.
苏斯看着家人的脸孔
Soze looks over the faces of his family.
他让这帮人见识了什么才是真正的意志
Then he showed these men of will what will really was.
他说他情愿看着家人死去…
He tells them he would rather see his family dead...
总比屈辱求存好得多
...than live another day after this.
他放走最后那个匈牙利人…
He lets the last Hungarian go...
等安葬了妻儿后，然后找这班党徒逐一报复
...waits until his family is in the ground, and goes after the rest of the mob.
他杀了他们的孩子，杀了他们的妻子…
He kills their kids, he kills their wives...
…杀了他们的父母及其朋友
...he kills their parents and their friends.
烧掉他们的居所…
He burns down the houses they live in...
…及他们工作的店
...and the stores they work in.
甚至还杀那些欠他们钱的人…
He kills people that owe them money. And like that...
…然后就消失了
...he's gone, underground.
自此再没人见过他， 他变成了一个神话
Nobody's ever seen him since. He becomes a myth.
一个罪犯们晚上给孩子说的故事
A spook story that criminals tell their kids at night.
“要是不听话， 凯撒·苏斯就会来抓你”
"Rat on your pop, and Keyser Soze will get you."
没有人相信这事
No one ever really believes.
你相信有这人吗？
Do you believe in him?
基顿总是说:
Keaton always said:
“我不信上帝，但我怕他”
"I don't believe in God, but I'm afraid of him."
我信上帝
I believe in God.
唯一让我恐惧的就是凯撒·苏斯
And the only thing that scares me is Keyser Soze.
你对此有何看法？
You give any weight to this?
我会给你介绍法院的丹曼徹斯特
I can introduce you to Dan Metzheiser from Justice.
他有些关于苏斯在华盛顿的资料，收集那家伙的资料几乎成了他的业余爱好
He's got a file on Soze in DC. It's been a hobby of his for a while.
大多数人视他为『怪杰胡克』中的那个记者
A lot of guys equate him to that reporter on The Incredible Hulk.
你听过他的事吗？
You've heard of him?
哪儿？在街上？
Where? On the street?
听过几次，都是无关痛痒的事
A few times. You know, outside stuff.
有些人间接为苏斯工作， 并赚了点钱
Someone working for a guy who worked for a guy who got money from Soze.
就是那样
Shit like that.
就像是种古老的象征， 一种驱魔印
It could be an old badge. A hex sign.
这名字就是为了让人躲的远远的
Keep people from fucking with you when a name meant something.
- 但你已插手这事  - 没错
- But you're here. - Shit, yeah.
这家伙因为害怕苏斯，甚至想从医院里逃走
This guy's trying to walk out of a hospital because he's so afraid of Soze.
我会提高警觉的
I'll run it up the flagpole.
我是清白的，我已经说了船上的事
I came clean. I told it like it happened.
再说去那儿的过程又有什么用 ？
So what about how I got there?
地方检察官也曾威胁我别指望特赦
It's so full of holes, the DA would've told me to forget amnesty.
你从我身上得到了想要的情报，已经赚了
You got what you wanted out of me. Big deal.
- 为何没把这些情况向地方检察官坦白？ - 那么你和我说…
- That's why you never told the DA? - You tell me.
如果我向你说是尼斯湖怪雇的我，你会怎么想？
If I told you the Loch Ness monster hired me, what would you say?
推翻证供，我们会召你作证
Turn state's evidence. We'll put you on the stand.
我已经获释了，你还能给我开什么条件？
I've got immunity. What can you possibly offer me?
若真有凯撒·苏斯其人，他会来找你的
If there really is a Keyser Soze, he's gonna come lookin' for you.
你有没有大脑？
Where's your head?
你以为事情就那么简单？
Where do you think the pressure is?
无论你称呼他凯撒·苏斯或是什么， 他都知道我身在何处
Keyser Soze, or whatever you call him, knows where I am right now.
他能在十分钟里就把我找出来，然后逼你放人
He has the burner on your ass to let me go so he can scoop me up 10 minutes later.
特赦也就是你们这些混蛋想出来的
Immunity was just a deal with you assholes.
若我被假释，我就有了新麻烦
I got a new problem when I post bail.
为何让他玩弄于股掌之间？ 我们能保护你
Why play into his hands? We can protect you.
多谢了，大卫，你说的太动听了
Thanks, Dave. Bang-up job so far. Extortion, coercion.
若要你吻我屁股，我也不反对的
Pardon me if I ask you to kiss my pucker.
把我赶至穷途末路的人，居然说要保护我？
The same fuckers that rounded us up are now bailing me out?
去你的
Fuck you.
你以为你能逮住凯撒·苏斯？
You think you can catch Keyser Soze?
你以为像他这样的人会束手就擒吗
You think a guy like that comes this close to getting caught...and sticks his head out?
若他真要出现，那就是为了除掉我
If he comes up for anything, it'll be to get rid of me.
然后…
After that...
…我想你再也不会听到他的消息
...my guess is you'll never hear from him again.
后来怎样了？
What happened next?
我们第二天醒来，范斯特已经走了
We woke up the next morning and Fenster was gone.
他不想为苏斯卖命
He couldn't handle the idea of slumming for Soze.
他留下字条祝我们好运…
He left us a note wishing us good luck...
…还拿走了我们抢来的所有钱
...and took a chunk of the money we'd scraped together.
然后怎样？
Then what?
麦克麦纳斯很愤怒
McManus was furious.
说要把他捉回来剁碎他的心肝
He talked about tracking him down and ripping his heart out. All sorts of shit.
那晚我们接到一个电话
That night, we got the call.
什么电话？
What call?
小林说已经找到了范斯特
Kobayashi told us where we could find Fenster.
我们快离开这儿
Let's get the fuck out of here.
我们得先把他埋了
We gotta bury him.
用什么挖坑？
With what?
用我们的手
With our hands.
神经病
This is nuts.
这里全是干沙
It's dry fucking sand.
等他尸身腐烂时，一里外的冲浪者也能闻到尸臭
When he rots the surfers are gonna smell him a mile away.
- 给我挖 - 我们该怎么办？
- Dig, you fuck. - What are we gonna do?
这家伙想把我们全干了
This fuckin' guy is gonna kill us.
我不知道你的打算，跛子，但我要跑路，我没什么问题
I don't know about you, peg leg, but I can run. I got no problem with that.
小林要干掉你也没什么问题
Kobayashi doesn't seem to have a problem with it either.
你就走吧， 我们会为你挖另一个坑
You run, and we're gonna be diggin' a hole for you.
明白吗？
You got that?
死的又不是我亲儿子，我不欠任何人的！
This ain't my boy we're burying. I don't owe anybody!
- 去你的吧   - 我们在一起混了五年
- So fuck you. - He was my partner for five years.
所见过的钱比你想象的还多
We did more jobs and I saw more money than you can ever count.
你给我去死！
So fuck you!
- 所以现在才要还债！ - 这不是还债！
- 'Cause now it's payback! - It's not payback!
这只是警告
It's precaution.
想还债那就去还，想跑路的就跑吧，我不在乎
You want payback? You wanna run? I don't care.
我不是为范斯特这么做
I'm not doin' this for Fenster.
也不是为你们这么做
I'm not doin' it for you.
我只是为了我自己而已
I'm doin' this for me.
我得把事情全了结
I'm gonna finish this thing.
我不会让这叫小林的杂碎活下去
This Kobayashi bastard is not gonna stand on me.
范斯特被杀后，没有人逃跑？
After they killed Fenster, nobody would run?
- 我想的，我知道我们定能逃脱   - 那你为什么不说什么？
- I wanted to. I thought we could make it. - Why didn't you say anything?
相信我，我试了，但基顿不同意这么做
Believe me, I tried, but Keaton wouldn't have it.
我们很难劝服他
It was too far-fetched for him.
基顿很固执，他曾是警察
Keaton was a grounded guy. An ex-cop.
警察是不会接受复杂的解释的
To a cop, the explanation is never that complicated.
总是容易受骗
It's always simple.
不信街上的流言，不信幕后有黑手
There's no mystery to the street, no arch-criminal.
如果你发现一具死尸，并认定这是他兄弟干的，你很可能是对的
You got a body and think his brother did it, you're probably right.
没人与基顿争论
Nobody argued with Keaton.
人人都准备好好的教训小林
They just set their minds to whacking Kobayashi.
他们上来了
They're coming up.
- 收到了吗？他上来了   - 他正下来
- Did you hear me? He's coming up. - He's on his way down.
别动
Don't move.
按二十楼，快
Press 20. Do it now.
出去
Move.
- 我们的答复是“不行”   - 苏斯先生会很--
- The answer is "no." - Mr.Soze will be most--
听着，混蛋，根本没有凯撒·苏斯这个人
Listen, cocksucker, there is no Keyser Soze.
要再提这名字，我就立马杀了你
Mention his name again, I'll kill you right now.
真是奇怪， 我以为你们是为了杀我而来
A strange threat. I assume you've come here to kill me anyway.
我知道你找的到我们…
We know that you can get to us...
…可现在你也知道了，我们能找到你
...but now you know that we can get to you.
我最后给你次机会去终止此事
I'm giving you one last chance to call this off.
我的雇主已经决定了
My employer has made up his mind.
- 他不会改变主意的   - 我们也不会
- He does not change it. - Neither do we.
你能杀范斯特，但你杀不了我们所有人
You got Fenster, but you won't be able to get all of us.
至少在我们中的某个干掉你之前不会
Not before one of us gets through to you.
我信你的话，是真的相信
I believe you. I most sincerely do.
若你们不是有能耐的人，就不会被选进来
You would not have been chosen were you not so suitable.
但我不能做这决定，无论你怎样…
But I cannot make this decision. Whatever you threaten me with is...
…恐吓我都会于事无补
...ludicrous in comparison to what will be done to me...
…因我必须完全执行命令
...if I do not carry out my orders in full.
想杀你的人就是我
I'm the guy that's gonna get you.
我只想你知道那点
I just wanted you to know that.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
就当是我在恳求，请相信我
I implore you, believe me...
…苏斯先生确有其人
...Mr.Soze is very real...
- …而他是个很坚决的人   - 我们等着瞧吧
- ...and very determined. - We'll see.
在你干掉我之前…
Before you do me in...
…请允许我先去了结与菲娜琳小姐的公事好吗？
...you will let me finish my business with Miss Finneran first, won't you?
你说什么？
What did you say?
伊迪·菲娜琳
Edie Finneran.
她正在楼上我的办公室…
She's upstairs in my office...
…等着交涉一桩引渡案
...for an extradition deposition.
她要求我亲自与她谈这案子
I requested she be put on the case personally.
她是昨天飞来洛杉矶的
She flew in yesterday.
没关系
No matter.
动手吧
Kill away.
你在说谎
You're lying.
有吗？
Am I?
菲娜琳小姐在洛杉矶期间，将受到很好的保护
Miss Finneran's escort while she's here in Los Angeles.
保镖会片刻不离其左右
Never leaves her for a moment.
我想你也会高兴，她的安全受到保障
I thought you'd be glad to know she's in good hands.
好好休息去吧，船会在星期五到
Get some rest. The boat will be ready for you on Friday.
若你或你的朋友，有任何轻举妄动
If I see you or any of your friends before then...
…菲娜琳小姐将会饱受折磨而死
...Miss Finneran will be the victim of a most gruesome violation before she dies.
哈肯尼先生，你的父亲…
As indeed will your father, Mr.Hockney...
…还有肯特先生在亚里桑那州的叔叔也会如此
...and your Uncle Randall in Arizona, Mr.Kint.
我还会亲手阉掉麦克麦纳斯先生的侄子
I might only castrate Mr.McManus' nephew, David.
你们都清楚了吗？
Do I make myself clear?
我们会处理楼下那两具尸体
We will take care of the two bodies downstairs.
并会把那账算到范斯特先生身上
We'll add them to the cost of Mr.Fenster.
请恕失陪，各位
If you'll excuse me, gentlemen.
这真是场怪异的恶梦
It's a logistical nightmare.
约有十到二十人
Close quarters. 10, maybe 20 men.
我们估计不到船舱内还有多少人
There's no tellin' how many more are gonna be below deck.
要偷袭那些家伙吗？
Can we stealth these guys?
因为是毒品交易，他们会小心防范的
With all that coke, they're gonna be ready.
而且会带给我们另一个问题
Which brings me to sunny point Number 2.
即使我们偷袭成功并劫走那船，还是会一无所得
Even if one of us gets through and jacks the boat, we still got nothin'.
等他们收了钱又如何？
What if we wait for the money?
那至少要再多干掉十个人
Ten more men at least.
以我看来，这行不通
In my opinion, it can't be done.
谁进去了都不会活着出来
Anyone who goes in is not comin' out alive.
- 我会等钱到再下手   - 我也是
- I'm gonna wait for the money. - Me, too.
- 你们有听他在说吗？    - 既然进去了，就没指望全身而退
- Did you hear what he just said? - If I'm goin' in, I want a cut.
我也是
Me, too.
天下没有办不成的事
There's nothing that can't be done.
真不敢相信我们就这样直接去送死
I just can't believe we're gonna walk in to certain death.
电台里说纽约正在下雨
The news said it's raining in New York.
他们说的那是什么话？
What language is that?
不知道，可能是俄语
I don't know. Russian, I think.
好象是匈牙利语
Hungarian?
各位，包裹已经送到了
The package has arrived, gentlemen.
你们准备好了吗？
You kids ready?
若不是停下来答你，就已经预备好了
I would be if I didn't have to stop and answer you.
我已经准备妥当
I'm ready.
麦克麦纳斯，你要在十秒内搞定
McManus, you better be set up in 10 seconds.
准备好了
I'm ready.
我要你留在这里
I want you to stay here.
我本来要掩护--
I'm supposed to cover--
如果我们出不来了， 带上钱赶快走
If we don't get out of this, take the money and go.
我不能--
I can't--
去找伊迪，告诉她全部真相
Find Edie. Tell her everything that happened.
她认识许多人，她知道该如何处理
She knows people. She knows what to do.
如果用我的方法除不掉小林， 那么她有别的办法
If I don't get Kobayashi my way, she'll get him her way.
- 可要是我--   - 按我说的去做
- What if I-- - Just do what I say.
拜托了
Please.
告诉她….
Tell her that...
告诉她我已经尽力了
Tell her I tried.
麦克麦纳斯，他过来了
McManus, he's on his way.
我已经就位
I'm there.
一，二，三，四…
One, two, three, four...
…五，六，七…
...five, six, seven...
奥斯瓦德的活不好干啊
Oswald was a fag.
你好
Hi.
你好吗？
How you doin'?
有什么问题吗？
Is there a problem?
快
Now.
王二先生有块地
"Old McDonald had a farm
咿呀咿呀呦
"Ee-aye, ee-aye, O
“在那地里他杀了班人”
"And on that farm, he shot some guys"
明星要出场了
Elvis has left the building.
别开枪，别开枪，自己人
Hold fire. Hold fire. Vamonos!
好啊
Hello.
你为何不逃？
Why didn't you run?
我被吓呆了
I froze up.
我想起了范斯特被埋葬时的样子
I thought about Fenster and how he looked when we buried him.
然后我又想到基顿，那时候看起来他离成功不远
Then I thought about Keaton, and it looked like he might pull it off.
有个男孩在沙滩上发现一具尸体
A boy found a body on the beach today.
是被人从船上抛下海的，头部中了两枪
Thrown clear of the boat. Shot twice in the head.
事物局的两个人去鉴定了他的身份
Two guys from the Bureau identified him.
- 然后呢？   - 他叫阿尔图罗·马奎斯
- What else? - His name was Arturo Marquez.
是个阿根廷走私犯
A petty smuggler from Argentina.
去年在纽约曾因走私而被捕
He was arrested last year in New York for trafficking.
他逃往加州，但在长岛被捉回
He escapes to California. They pick him up in Long Beach.
他们安排引渡他回国，但又被他逃脱
They're setting up extradition, he escapes again.
看看这个
Now, get this.
伊迪·菲娜琳提出的引渡建议
Edie Finneran's brought in to advise on the proceedings.
小林
Kobayashi
纽约传给了我一份马奎斯证供的复印件
New York faxed me a copy of his testimony.
- 他是个告密者   - 是个大叛徒
- He was a rat. - A big fucking rat.
阿尔图罗很害怕回到监狱
Arturo was very opposed to returning to prison.
甚至于他供出了将近五十个人
So much so, that he named close to 50 people.
猜猜最后的人名是谁？
Guess who he named in the finale.
凯撒·苏斯
Keyser Soze
还有
There's more.
我会把所知一切告诉你，若说重覆了就告诉我
I'll tell you what I know. Stop me when this sounds familiar.
船上根本就没有毒品
There was no dope on that boat.
待着别出声音
You, stay quiet.
他来了
He's here.
我知道他来了，就是他，我告诉你，就是他
I know he's here. That's him. I'm telling you, that's him.
我知道他来了！
I know he's here!
- 你不明白，是他   - 安静
- You can't understand. That's him. - Shut up.
就是他，你听到没？ 我告诉你，是凯撒·苏斯来了！
That's him. You hear me? I'm telling you, it's Keyser Soze!
- 哈肯尼在哪里？   - 我不知道
- Where's Hockney? - I don't know.
这儿没毒品
There's no coke.
- 什么？   - 你听得很清楚，该死的
- What? - You heard me, dumb fuck.
- 根本就没有毒品！   - 你到底什么意思？没有毒品？
- There's no coke! - What the fuck? No coke?
我已经仔细搜过了每间房
I've been up and down in every fucking room.
- 一定有的！   - 根本没有！
- There's gotta be coke! - There is nothing!
没有！
Nothing!
别跟我开玩笑了
Don't you fuck with me.
根本就没有毒品！
There is no fucking coke!
我要走了
I'm out of here.
我什么都没对他们说
I told them nothing.
我发誓我没有
I swear.
我什么也没说，求你了
I told them nothing. Please.
究竟是怎么回事？
What the fuck is goin' on?
这是真是太怪了
The strangest thing.
那就是你供词中所提到过的，那个穿西服的瘦男人？
That's what you said. You saw a man in a suit with a slim build.
等等
Wait a minute.
你说你看见了凯撒·苏斯？
Are you saying you saw Keyser Soze?
- 先前的证供里你说不知道那男人是谁   - 我知道船上肯定有毒品
- You said you didn't know who it was. - I know there was dope on that boat.
- 别再拖延时间   - 我没有
- Stop stallin'. - I'm not.
- 你明白我想知道什么   - 给我走开
- You know what I'm getting at. - Get out of my face.
我已经被豁免了，不需要再受你恐吓
I got immunity. I don't have to take this.
你明白我想知道什么
You know what I'm getting at.
- 我不知道你在说什么   - 说出真相！
- I don't know what you're talking about. - The truth!
告诉我是谁杀了基顿
Try to tell me you saw someone kill Keaton.
我说了
I did.
你在撒谎
You're lying to me.
- 你知道事实真相   - 我不知道你在说什么
- You've known this whole time. - I don't know what you're saying.
我看见基顿中了枪，我发誓
I did see Keaton get shot. I swear to you.
你为何不救他？你手上有枪
Why didn't you help him? You had a gun.
他可是你的朋友
He was your friend.
因为我害怕
Because I was afraid.
- 怕极了   - 你怕什么？
- Afraid. - Afraid of what?
- 怕什么--   - 我知道那是凯撒·苏斯
- Afraid of-- - I knew it was Keyser Soze.
是凯撒·苏斯，他是魔鬼的化身
It was Keyser Soze, I mean, the Devil himself.
你怎么敢在魔鬼的背后开枪？
How do you shoot the Devil in the back?
要是射不中又如何？
What if you miss?
那说回码头的事
Let's get back to the pier.
- 听说过阿尔图罗·马奎斯吗？   - 谁？没有
- Arturo Marquez. Ever hear of him? - What? No.
他是司法部的线人
He was a stool pigeon for the Justice Department.
他向联邦执行官录了份口供
He swore out a statement to federal marshals...
…说他见过并能认出…
...saying that he had seen and could positively identify one...
凯撒·苏斯
...Keyser Soze
这报告中还记载着
It says right here in the report.
他熟知凯撒·苏斯一切业务…
He had intimate knowledge of his businesses, including...
包括运毒及谋杀以外的事情
...but not exclusive to, drug trafficking and murder.
我从未听说过他
I never heard of him.
他的手下把他出卖给匈牙利党
His own people were selling him to a gang of Hungarians.
这班匈牙利人似乎被苏斯清除并赶回土耳其
Most likely the same Hungarians that Soze all but wiped out back in Turkey.
那钱并不是用来买毒品的
The money wasn't there for dope.
这班匈牙利人会收买…
The Hungarians were going to buy the one guy...
一个能把凯撒·苏斯治罪的人
...that could incriminate Keyser Soze.
- 我说了我从未听过他   - 但基顿听过
- I said I never heard of him. - But Keaton did.
伊迪·菲娜琳是马奎斯引渡案的顾问
Edie Finneran was Marquez's extradition advisor.
她知道他是谁，还知道他掌握的资料
She knew who he was and what he knew.
船上根本没有毒品，这只是次谋杀行动
There were no drugs on that boat. It was a hit.
这次自杀式的行动
A suicide mission to whack out the one guy...
…目的是去干掉这个能指证凯撒·苏斯的家伙
...that could finger Keyser Soze.
于是苏斯派了班贼去执行
So Soze put some thieves to it...
他算好了这班人一定会死
...men he knew he could march into certain death.
你说苏斯利用我们去杀人？
You're saying Soze sent us to kill someone?
我说就是基顿本人，他把你留在后面是有原因的
I'm saying Keaton did. He left you behind for a reason.
按我说的去做
Just do what I tell you.
既然无论跑到何处，苏斯都能找到你…
If you all knew that Soze could find you anywhere...
…为何还给你金钱逃亡？
...why did he give you the money to run?
- 他可以在船上就把你干掉   - 他不想我死
- He could have used you on the boat. - He wanted me to live.
一个过去的贪污警察
A one-time dirty cop without a loyalty in the world...
…竟然有颗挽救跛子贼的善心？
...finds it in his heart to save a worthless rat cripple?
这不可能，先生，你能给我理由吗？
No, sir. Why?
是因为伊迪
Edie.
我从头到尾就不信这个改过自新的故事
I don't buy that reform story for a minute.
就算我信这点…
Even if I did...
…我也不会相信他会派你去保护她
...I certainly don't believe he would send you to protect her.
给我个解释？
So why?
因为我们是朋友
Because he was my friend.
不，他不是你的朋友，基顿没有任何朋友
No, he wasn't your friend. Keaton didn't have friends.
你来这儿干什么？
What are you doing here?
他留下你的命，是因为他用的到你
He saved you because he wanted it that way.
这就是他的目的
It was his will.
- 基顿就是凯撒·苏斯   - 不是
- Keaton was Keyser Soze. - No.
只有他才能干掉哈肯尼和麦克麦纳斯这类角色
A man who could wrangle the wills of men like Hockney and McManus.
只有他才能轻松的在警局里安排指认
A man who could engineer a police lineup...through all his years of contacts in NYPD.
只有他才会残忍的杀害伊迪·菲娜琳
The kind of man who could've killed Edie Finneran.
她的尸体昨天在宾夕法尼亚州一间酒店被发现
She was found yesterday at a hotel in Pennsylvania...
…头部连中两枪而亡
...shot twice in the head.
现在你对基顿有何看法？
What do you think about Keaton now?
伊迪死了？
Edie?
他利用你们掩护他上船
He used all of you to get him on that boat.
这事他本来一个人做不了，他必须要亲自下手…
He couldn't get on alone. He had to pull the trigger himself...
…以确认干掉了那个…
...to make sure he got his man...
…能指认他的家伙
...the one man that could identify him.
全是胡说
This is all bullshit.
你说亲眼看见他死了
You said you saw him die.
肯定吗？
Or did you?
听到警车来到时，你想藏起来
You had to hide when you heard the police cars.
你说在起火前听到枪声…
You said you heard the shot before the fire...
…可你没看见他死
...but you didn't see him die.
- 我了解他，他绝不会--   - 他是在利用你
- I knew him. He would never-- - He programmed you.
他安排由你来说整个骗局
He programmed you to tell us what he wanted you to.
就如你说的，他知道我们问不出什么来
He knew we were close. You said it yourself.
保你出去的政治压力由何而来？
Where was the political pressure to protect you from?
就是基顿在幕后
It was Keaton.
- 被豁免就是给你的奖赏    - 但为什么偏偏是我？
- Immunity was your reward. - But why me?
为什么不挑范斯特，或是麦克麦纳斯和哈肯尼？
Why not Fenster or McManus or Hockney?
为什么是我？ 我又蠢又跛，为什么是我？
Why me? I'm stupid. I'm a cripple. Why me?
就因为你是个跛子
Because you're a cripple.
就因为你很愚蠢
Because you're stupid.
就因为你比他们没用
Because you're weaker than them.
要是他死了….
If he's dead...
要是你说的是真的，那么就没问题了
If what you say is true, then it won't matter.
袭击警车是不是他的主意？
It was his idea to hit the taxi service, wasn't it?
- 对我说实话    - 是基顿提出的
- Come on, tell me the truth. - It was all Keaton.
我们一直跟着他
We followed him from the beginning.
我不知道
I didn't know.
我看到他死了
I saw him die.
我也相信他已经死了
I believe he's dead. Christ.
你单独一人会不安全
You're not safe on your own.
你认为他是….
You think he's...
凯撒·苏斯
Keyser Soze?
我不知道
I don't know.
凯撒·苏斯只是个化名， 或就如你说的，是个传说
Keyser Soze's a shield, or like you said, a spook story.
但我很了解基顿，你一出去就有人等着干掉你
But I know Keaton, and someone is out there pulling strings for you.
- 别出去，让我们保护你    - 我才不当诱饵，我已经自由了
- Stay here and let us protect you. - I'm not bait. I post today.
二十分钟前你就可以走了
You posted 20 minutes ago.
里欧队长想你尽快离开这里
Capt. Leo wants you out of here.
- 除非你想翻供   - 我会把握机会的，谢了
- Unless you turn state's. - I'll take my chances.
如果有人想要干掉你，那他们一定要选在外面下手
If someone wants to get you, they're gonna get you out there.
若你改变口供，就再也不用害怕
Turn state's evidence. You might never see trial.
也许如此
Maybe so.
可我不是叛徒
But I'm not a rat.
该死的警察
Fuckin' cops.
能借用你的传真机吗？
Excuse me, can I use your fax machine?
请在这儿签个名，肯特先生
You'll have to sign for these, Mr.Kint.
一块金表
One watch, gold.
金打火机
One cigarette lighter, gold.
一包烟，谢谢
One pack of cigarettes. Thank you.
我们仍是一无所知
We still got nothing.
我知道了关于基顿的事
I know what I wanted to know about Keaton.
那毫无价值
Which is nothing.
没关系，他很快会知道我们了解了多少
No matter. He'll have to know how close we came.
不管凯撒·苏斯存不存在
Keyser Soze or no Keyser Soze...
…只要基顿还活着，他就不会再出现了
...if Keaton is alive, he's not comin' up again.
我会去找他
I'll find him.
那是浪费时间
Waste of time.
若是传闻不会平息， 那就不算是传闻了
A rumor's not a rumor that doesn't die.
什么？
What?
没什么
Nothing.
伙计，你这儿真够乱的
Man, you're a slob.
但东西摆放的都还有规律
But it all has a system.
要是全摆的整整齐齐的，就没有亲和力了
It all makes sense if you look at it right. You gotta stand back from it.
要看更恐怖的地方吗？到我车库去就知道了
You wanna see a real horror show? See my garage.
说服我，告诉我每个细节
Convince me. Tell me every last...
我曾经加入过在伊利诺州斯科基的一个男声四重唱组合…
When I was in that barbershop quartet in Skokie, Illinois...
- 你到底有没有大脑？   - 我们需要先思考周全，再想想
- Where's your head? - We need to think, think back.
我肯定你们已听过不少传言
I'm sure you've heard tall tales.
- 是布里克·马林   - 这事不对劲
- Bricks Marlin. - This isn't right.
- 我想听听你的故事   - 已经全说了
- I just wanna hear your story. - It's all there.
- 我说的都是实话   - 来自加州的，名叫雷德福特
- I'm tellin' it straight. - Some guy in California called Redfoot.
- 这是苏斯先生送上的礼物   - 老实对我说
- A gift from Mr.Soze. - Talk to me.
- 那雷德福特呢？   - 雷德福特先生并不知情汇报
- What about Redfoot? - Mr.Redfoot knew nothing.
- 利用不知情的人…   - 是个超级大胖子
- Using pawns... - A big fat guy. Like, orca fat.
还有个律师…
There was a lawyer...
叫小林
Kobayashi...
我曾在危地马拉尝过咖啡豆磨的新鲜咖啡
When I was picking beans in Guatemala we made fresh coffee.
- 我知道你认为他是好人 - 我知道他很好
- I know you thought he was a good man. - I know he was good.
- 告诉我全部的细节 - 这事怪极了
- You tell me every last detail. - The strangest thing.
你怎么敢在魔鬼的背后开枪？
How do you shoot the Devil in the back?
这家伙的后台很硬
This guy is protected from up on high by the Prince of...
说说你的故事，拐脚佬
What's your story, pretzel man?
- 还有个律师    - 什么律师？
- There was a lawyer. - What lawyer?
我就是小林
I am Mr.Kobayashi.
- 小林，小林，   - 告诉我所有的细节
- Kobayashi. Kobayashi. - Tell me every last detail.
- 我为凯撒·苏斯做事，   - 说服我，说服我
- I work for Keyser Soze. - Convince me. Convince me.
所有犯罪的大小角色
Every creep and scumbag that works the street...
…都会知道维伯·肯特的大名
...will know the name of Verbal Kint.
你见过那跛子吗？
The cripple, did you see him?
- 那跛子！他朝那里走了？ - 他往那边去了
- The cripple! Which way did he go? - He went out that way.
我知道你知情，我还知道你没说实话…
I know you know something. I know you're not telling...
我比你聪明
I'm smarter than you...
…不管你是否愿意，我都会找到我要的答案
...and I'm gonna find out whether you like it or not.
警察是不会接受复杂的解释的
To a cop, the explanation is never complicated.
- 总是那么容易受骗   - 真相
- It's always simple. - The truth!
根本就没什么幕后主使
There's no arch-criminal behind it all.
那个人有这能力，能够掌握…
Somebody with power, somebody who is capable...
凯撒·苏斯
Keyser Soze!
你以为像他这样的人会束手就擒吗？
You think a guy like that gets this close to getting caught...and sticks his head out?
就是因为你愚蠢，就因为你是跛子
Because you're stupid. Because you're a cripple.
现在我想知道那跛子是谁？
What I wanna know is, who's the gimp?
你完全知道事实真相
You've known the whole fuckin' time.
要是他来也是要找我， 我肯定基顿已经死了
If he comes up for anything it'll be for me. I'm sure Keaton is dead.
我的双腿没有知觉，凯撒
I can't feel my legs, Keyser.
干这行我学会的第一件事知道是什么吗？
First thing I learned on the job. You know what?
- 就是如何辨认凶手   - 你见到那个跛子了吗？
- How to spot a murderer. - You got the cripple in there?
- 他有提到凯撒·苏斯吗？   - 谁？
- Did he mention Keyser Soze? - Who?
那之后…
After that...
…我猜之后再听不到他的消息
...my guess is you'll never hear from him again.
最巧妙之处就是能让人相信他不存在
The greatest trick the Devil ever pulled...was convincing the world he didn't exist.
然后就象那样…
And like that...
…消失的无影无踪
...he's gone